Adam Hoar

07584 573146

Adam.hoar@icloud.com

PROFILE

Software Engineering Bootcamp Graduate, originally coming from a background in Asset Management and Startups.

As a Full Stack Developer I get to do the things I genuinely enjoy; solving tough problems with creative solutions, being part of a team that works to build amazing things and constantly learning as I go.

Having worked on a range of projects I have experience in Test Driven Development, Object Oriented Programming, both Front and Back End, Javascript, React, Node, Express, Ruby, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Jest, Cypress and RSpec. In my own time working on some Python projects utilising Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib and Tensorflow.

Before joining Makers I was employee #4 at a Health Care startup where I gained first hand experience in Agile, worked on sprint planning and helping to debug the platform. Additionally, I developed as a leader over time, ultimately managing a large team of people both in the field and in person. Key to our collective success was communication, adapting quickly to new situations, learning from our mistakes and executing on our long term vision.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Student — November 2022 - March 2023

Makers is an intensive 4 month bootcamp created and run by industry leading engineers. Producing language agnostic, self-sufficient software engineers.

Teaching key concepts such as Test Driven Development, Object Oriented Programming and Agile. This was taught in conjunction with Full Stack Development using Javascript, React, Node, Ruby and much more.

Working to tight time frames we completed a range of individual, paired programming and team work.

For a full portfolio please visit my GitHub repo at www.github.com/amh4

Operations Manager, Lifted, London — March 2020 - November 2021

Building out new systems and process across the business. Included projects like automating our Recruitment Funnel, building a Sales Pipeline and our own Track & Trace System.

Helped shape the overall direction, sprint planning, bug capture/prioritisation across our apps. Working closely with our Tech Team we would map out what needed to covered in upcoming sprints to match business needs, organise testing parties before rollouts and help with the rollout of new features across the business.

Adopted Agile methodologies for my own team such as daily standups and weekly retros. Whilst not being a tech team this helped us have great visibility over a large range of responsibilities. The weekly retros allowed us to objectively look at how we worked which was crucial to being able to adapt and deal with the consistent fast growth of the company.

Operations Analyst, Lifted, London — August 2019 - March 2020

Worked closely with our Tech Team on our web app and mobile apps. Included helping plot the roadmap of feature rollouts, recording and reporting on bugs and passing these changes on to our Carers in the field.

Oversaw the day-to-day management of our Carers across London. Starting with 5-10 Carers which grew to 25-30 in these early months. Integral to this was quickly building relationships and getting them to buy into our collective mission. From this buy in we were able to really push our growth to help more people.

Created a Python Programme to harness the data we had to start delivering pro-active healthcare.

Operations Associate, Parmenion Capital Partners — February 2018 - June 2018

Part of the team responsible for processing all client asset movements accounting for millions of pounds each day.

Stringent attention to detail with all capital allocations as all daily transactions of millions had to reconcile to the exact correct amount.

There was a strong culture of accountability and decisive action which helped to build trust both internally and externally. Where any issues were encountered an incident log would be recorded. Analysing why the issue arose, whether it was likely to occur again, our immediate action to resolve it as well as the permanent fix.

Investment Consultant — 2000–2002

Established and developed relationships with clients from a range of backgrounds through face-to-face meetings, phone calls and emails.

Research and provide information on complex investment products to aid the investment decisions of our clients.

Responsible for training new Consultants, one-to-one's and performance reviews.

Won several competitions for new business brought onto the platform.

Proprietary Trader G7 Currency Markets — December 2014 - November 2016

Responsible for investing \$6 million per week in trading volume across all G7 Currency pairs.

Rapidly process information to make balanced investment decisions with solid risk management.

Was the first trader to test out the remote working trading platform. Executing all trades off premises, testing the platform, reporting on issues and suggesting additional features to implement.

EDUCATION

University of Plymouth — MSc Finance - Merit (2:1 Equivalent)

Advanced calculus such as the Black-Scholes Model.

Financial Statement Analysis

Modern Portfolio Theory

Statistics/Econometrics

Thesis that involved processing 15 years of exchange rate data to model the effectiveness of various trading strategies.

BSc Economics

Dissertation on whether Premier League Strikers are under or over(?!) paid. Spoiler alert: Some are actually underpaid...somehow

Microeconomic Theory: Opportunity Cost, Production, Innovation and Supply/Demand Model

Macroeconomic Theory: Classical Economics, Keynesian, Austrian, International Trade

Game Theory

HOBBIES

Going outside my comfort zone. Going to countries where I don't speak the language, no phone data and just going for it. Recently visiting the Matterhorn and we plan on going to Everest next year. I have played golf, tennis, football, rugby, American football, squash and my knees certainly feel like it. If you hire me apologies for the sound I make as I stand up from my chair, it's involuntary.